<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ryan Cohen</title>
  <id>http://imryan.net</id>
  <link href="http://imryan.net" />
  <link href="http://imryan.net/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2014-02-18T16:31:58-05:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, Ryan Cohen</rights>
  <author>
    <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/time" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you deeply think about it, what is time? A measurement of life, a countdown, what is it? We may never know, and as much as we try to understand it – we are wasting it. Living is about making the days count, not just counting the days on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I waste away my predetermined time on this earth, I still find myself wishing to be back in a previous state of life. In a time where I had no idea that would mean this much to me in the near future. If only I had prematurely known so, I would’ve spoken the words that have longed to be said, done the things that have longed for action, and most importantly, made the days count. For as young as I was in those days, I still could’ve made them count for more than I had; I could’ve given them an even stronger meaning than what they stand for now. But in the end, I’m left with remorse for wasting away at what would later be known as the best years of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I try to make sure this won’t occur once more, I find myself still wasting away precious time. No matter how hard I attempt to create a new volume of great memories in my mind, nothing tops the collection of historical pieces I have once put together. The worst part about it is, I have no clue what caused it all. What was it that made these days so great to me? I wish I was able to recall it, I really do. It seems as if things will never be as great as they once were back then. Funny part is, I can never go back to those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m frequently lead to believe that aging played a huge role in my nostalgic personality. Things changed so quickly for me that I couldn’t keep up with time; leaving me unable to enjoy it all while I had it. I felt as if things would be that way forever, which left me taking every moment I had for granted. I wish I could go back in time and redo everything in its entirety, my life would be so different. It would be better. Don’t get me wrong, I love life and everything about it. But sometimes I wish it were different, all for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only I could go back to 2006. If only I could say the things I was always scared to, and do the things I never thought I would do. If only I could start fresh, and have nothing on my slate or anything in front of me. I wish I could change the way people thought when they read or heard my name. To this day that is all I wish for; to undo all of my previous actions and words, to start over as an unknown individual just waiting to make a new name for itself. But in the real world, things do not go this way; and because of this, I remain full of previous actions and words that I should not have said nor have done.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/time</id>
      <updated>2013-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Life</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/life" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many perceive that the purpose of life is solely to become successful, make a name for yourself, or to even become rich. These things are all totally wrong. Truth is, there is no purpose to life. None at all. We are all just entities placed around the world, bundled with a clean slate, a clean conscience, and a clean record. We may not have a fixed purpose, but we all do have goals; and these goals may even determine what our purpose really is, but until then, the purpose is just empty. It is left for us to fulfill, and the fun part is, we may fill it in any way we wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being blessed with the gift that is life, we are free to roam the earth’s soil, build on it, and even change it. We’re all just people, and we are all interconnected with each other. While we may not be the same physically or mentally, we all share the gift of life, and the gift of being a person in this world. When it comes to being different, some people may be better than others at something, while some may not. But when it comes to being the same, we all do differ in many ways, and that’s why life is an adventure. If we all were the exact same, there would be nothing new in the world, nothing exciting. But because of being an individual with various skills, opinions, appearances, and more, we are all unique in our own ways. Life is out there, and if you take the time to appreciate it, you’d be amazed at what you find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this article is really just to send a message to the reader. With that being said, my message to you is simple: just be happy. As brief and to the point as it is, it’s very effective if you truly think about it. Live more simply, and learn to take a load off of your daily plate of problems. Do things that you truly love to do, and make time for these things daily. We all have only one life to live, so why waste it being sad or doing things that don’t even matter to you? I feel as if most people take life for granted, and almost feel as if we’d get another. Before you state the obvious in your own minds, just consider it. Are we really appreciating the lives we live as much as we should be? I think not. And so I believe it’s time, even for myself, to start seeing it for its true beauty, and start living it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I’d like to touch is the idea about money. Money will most certainly not buy you happiness, as cliché as it sounds, it is very true. No matter how many times one will repeat it, they still strive to prove it wrong, and achieve happiness from personal purchases. Sure, items we’ve always dreamed of having will always make us happy, but is it really happiness? Or are we just getting the sense of being happy mixed up with the actual meaning of happiness? I couldn’t tell you that; it is up to you to decide for yourself. But anyway, the true feeling of happiness comes from living life itself, and it is, in fact, something we can control. No matter who the person is that you are today, that person could transition into an even better one by the morning. As crazy as it sounds, I do believe in it. I’m all for personal improvement, and it is something that I am still making myself accustomed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap things up, the sole purpose of this post is to just teach yourself to be happy. No matter what is possibly going on in your life, nothing is too powerful enough to override happiness. I see it to be one of the strongest emotions that humans have, and so should you. Try going a day without complaining and see how your positivity changes. Try something new and different for once.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/life</id>
      <updated>2013-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Takeoff</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/takeoff" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know what they say, &quot;you can achieve whatever you put your mind to&quot;, and I have. Since  around the end of my sophomore year, I&#39;ve been pushing for a club focused around computer science. They always told me &quot;take it up with mrs.blah&quot;, &quot;I don&#39;t know about this&quot;, &quot;I&#39;m not sure if this is possible&quot;, etc. In life, I&#39;ve learned to be independent for the most part, and I&#39;ve also learned that if you want something done, do it yourself. With that being said, I took matters into my own hands, making myself almost ignorant to the skeptical comments placed onto my idea, and achieved my goal. Back in August, I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imryan.net/blog/csclub/&quot;&gt;blog entry&lt;/a&gt; regarding my idea, and since then, I&#39;ve been more than dedicated to its creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, trying to get it started was a big hassle. I had to annoy my guidance counselor over the summer so that she&#39;d forward my request on to the head faculty of my school. She then proceeded to forward my original email, but received no response back, from any of them. I was honestly surprised, because here&#39;s a student that wants to help educate others in a certain field, and the school doesn&#39;t support that? It was only after I repeatedly showed up in the guidance office every other day pushing my idea, that it was granted. I was scheduled a meeting with our principal the following week, and until then, I was always prepared at any time to be summoned to her office. Whilst doing work in math class, I was randomly called down, and I knew what for. This was it, my time to persuade and motivate. When I sat down in the office, she began asking me simple questions, which was already much easier than I thought it would be. &quot;You want to start up a computer science club?&quot; &quot;Yes.&quot; &quot;Find a teacher by Monday and you got it.&quot; &quot;Friday.&quot; &quot;Done.&quot; The end. That simple thirty-second conference is all that I pushed for this whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I took my time heading back to class, I began to brainstorm some possible teachers that would be interested in supervising the club. At first I thought my CS teacher, but when I explained it all to her, she was still very skeptical about it, having many concerns about the club. I had a negative feeling about her final decision, so the next morning I spoke with my tech problem solving teacher, Mr.Engle. For all of you who don&#39;t know Todd, he is the man. Before I could even finish explaining to him, he had already agreed AND went on to show me an email he received regarding a NASA robot building competition that he felt would be a perfect first project for the newly-formed club. He also hastily put his room up as an offer to be our new headquarters. This was it; we had acquired all of the necessities to run the club. After school, I began working on the first flyer to be displayed around school advertising the club&#39;s initial creation. Here&#39;s a sneak-peek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/iPGKswY.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is also special about the club, is that it happens to be the first-ever computer science club in our school district. I hope to take this club far, and spread the wondrous thing that is computer science. My highest goal in life is to change the world somehow, and through determination and ambition, one day I will achieve my goal. By doing small things, we are one step closer to getting where we desire to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/takeoff</id>
      <updated>2013-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Nostalgia</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/nostalgia" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am constantly brought back into the past by my frequent nostalgia, and sometimes I allow it to take the best of me. Dating back to when I was younger, I have always had an interest for time. Ranging from historic pieces to current timestamps, time was intriguing to me, and it still continues to be. Whenever I see a piece of literature, artwork, photo or video, I immediately search for its creation date, and my mind instantly gets set back to that time. I suddenly remember almost every detail of that day, whether it be how I was feeling, what I was doing, or even what the aroma was. I am mentally set back in time to the date. As weird as it sounds, it is true. There are days where I will smell an aroma I remember smelling from 2nd grade, and suddenly remember the day I first smelt it. I&#39;m making myself sound like a freak for actually putting this all out, but ever since I was 9 years old, I&#39;ve wanted to actually put all of this out. Ironically, I even remember the exact moment I first thought of logging this as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you close out of my blog and forever view me as &quot;that weird kid&quot;, just remember that I simply cannot control it. It&#39;s something I was born with, and is not a result from a previous action from my own doing. What I hate most about my mental time machine is that it can easily alter my mood, forcing me to become an emotional rollercoaster which sets me off in multiple directions at a time. I often hate my mentality, but sometimes it comes in handy when I need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, I cannot remember the very first instance of this happening, but I do remember the first time I made a mental timestamp that I&#39;ll never forget. It was the first day of 5th grade at my old elementary school. I was sitting in a wooden desk on the left side of the classroom next to my friend Connor. The light was just able to peak over the side of the white stone blocks on the wall seen just outside of the window. It shone through the screen on the window, then through the glass, making visible all of the dust particles. It shone directly onto my wooden desktop as I sat there. The aroma was a subtle old home smell, very soft and flat. I remember studying the entire room with my eyes, reading into my memory every detail surrounding me, so that I could forever remember the day. Well, it happened, and still continues to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never imagined that from that day on, everywhere I go and do will place a permanent memory on my brain. You know, I guess that&#39;s just the brain&#39;s job, but I feel as if my memories go a bit further than so. I wouldn&#39;t say these constant memories are ruining my life, but they often do interfere with my well-being, and it seldom frightens me. Just picture it: every ambience you ever come into contact with instantly being imprinted onto your brain, just to be referenced one day in the future when something similar is presented to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the things that I&#39;ve always wanted to log, dating back to around 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/nostalgia</id>
      <updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/beginnings" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of school, and it was very exciting. We all got to see our friends again, find out who we know that&#39;s in our classes, and begin the new semester. I&#39;m really looking forward to my first period class, Tech Problem Solving. We build hardware based around energy and transportation, and research ways to improve them. I&#39;m not too sure if any actual code will be involved in the design process, but either way it&#39;s still going to be awesome. I&#39;ll gain a general understanding of how computers work internally, and even get to build something myself. My teacher that I have is also a very intelligent guy, and has a lot of experience working in the technology field. I am very eager to get started already, after being pumped up on the first day with graphs on the design process and the course outline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second period I have Algebra 2, which I am also excited for believe it or not. As a developer, math is often handy to know on the spot, and can really help out in really any piece of software you could be writing. During freshman year, I took Algebra 1, but those were the days where I thought it was all stupid, and could care less. I wish I would&#39;ve put more effort in during freshman year, but there&#39;s no going back now. I feel as if I patched that rough patch up when sophomore year came around, when I B+ averaged every class. This year I&#39;m hoping to achieve more than my best; I&#39;m going for the gold, and nothing can prevent me from doing so. My goal for my junior year is to finish with A&#39;s overall, but a B here and there will still be appreciated in my grading portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third period class is English 3, which I can already tell will be great. Ever since I was in the first grade, I&#39;ve loved literature. Whether it be writing stories, reading, or even writing blog posts, I admire rich content. I know that telling by my blog that is not seen due to my short entries, but I&#39;m hoping to change that from now on. So anyway, we have a great teacher who I believe is new to our school, and I hope nothing but the best for her career here. She is very kind as well as intelligent, as she portrayed during class today. I look forward to having her as my teacher, as we complete the current semester and prepare for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.state.nj.us/education/assessment/hs/hspa/&quot;&gt;NJ HSPA&lt;/a&gt; test we take around March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on to fourth period, computer science. Possibly the best period of the day (no offense to any of my other instructors). As you may have read in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imryan.net/blog/csclub/&quot;&gt;earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt; I was rather excited to be taking part in the class. Like last year, we can&#39;t work with any code until Friday, due to the JDK profile not being installed on our new school computers beforehand. So today during class we just messed around as usual doing nothing for the most part. We have the same teacher as we did last year, and I&#39;m excited to have her again as well. Switching teachers can often get confusing, due to the variation in teaching styles. The only downside to the class is that Computer Science 1 and Computer Science 2 are now &lt;strong&gt;one conjoined class&lt;/strong&gt;. The school district dropped the original CS 1 class, where we learned VB.NET 1998, and switched it to Java. Corresponding to that change, now CS 2 cannot learn more than CS 1 because they just started Java and now so are we; so it&#39;s back to the basics, just in another language. I&#39;m looking to take AP Computer Science either this year or next, depending on if I even can take it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/beginnings</id>
      <updated>2013-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>School</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/school" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As summer begins to come to an end, the upcoming school year is approaching rather quickly. I for one, am actually very excited for my junior year. Whether it&#39;s because I&#39;ll be learning new things or seeing my friends, I am looking forward to living the student life again. My first semester will definitely be awesome, because I have two computer classes out of the four total classes I have per day. The thought of being in computer science again really gets me going, and I can&#39;t wait to be problem solving during school each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also passed my drivers test earlier in the week, so I&#39;ve been cruising around the shore lately. Feels great having freedom, as well as the ability to get from point A to point B independently, and when I would like to. It also teaches responsibilty and gives me a good sense of direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as my programming life goes, I haven&#39;t been working on much lately. I feel as if I can only really get into hard work if I&#39;m building something big, but other than that, I still do it a few hours each day anyway. I&#39;ve mainly been working on a piece of software for the office I work at, which allows my coworkers to reserve conference rooms, demo computers, and other things. It makes things easier for them knowing who has the item from when and till when exactly. I wrote the program in C#, and is also my first project I&#39;ve ever built that was in another language besides Objective-C. I hope to have it installed on the company computers before the end of the month, as it reaches its final completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also plan on updating my blog way more than I usually do this year. Even though I just ramble on about my day and the things I do, I find it fun putting my thoughts on paper (HTML paper).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/school</id>
      <updated>2013-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/birthday" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Good morning everyone, hope you&#39;re all off to a great start this morning as I am. Today&#39;s my 17th birthday and I can&#39;t believe it! I&#39;m spending the day working at the office until later, when I&#39;m going out for sushi with my mom. I&#39;m extremely tired, probably due to the fact I fell asleep past 12:30 this morning, and because I&#39;ve been getting up early all week for work. Tomorrow morning at 9 I go for my driving test to get my license, and I couldn&#39;t be more excited. Nervous as hell, but extremely excited. I already have a car that I will be using, that we purchased from my neighbor a few years ago. I&#39;m very thankful to have a working vehicle at the time I get my license, and I&#39;m excited to start using it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School is also starting in a few days on September 9th, which I am also pretty excited for. I&#39;m in classes that I like a lot, so it should be a fun year. This is also the most important year of high school as well, so all my effort will really count this time. I&#39;m taking a technical problem solving class first period, and Computer Science II fourth period during the first semester. I am so excited to go back into CS, I missed it a lot. My good friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyvillanueva.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Joey&lt;/a&gt; and I will definitely be working together to solve code problems throughout the semester, which will be awesome. I am also looking forward to learning more and bettering my skills during the upcoming schoolyear.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/birthday</id>
      <updated>2013-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>CS Club</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/csclub" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I found out my high school offered computer science last year, I was all over it. I read the page (which has no information on it at all), harassed my teachers, and put in an early request to have that class in the upcoming semester. First semester of my sophomore year I took Computer Science I. We learned 1998 Visual Basic programming. Classic, right. Needless to say, I still loved it. I wish it were still the early 90s or late 80s, when tech was still just getting fired up. After working with VB, I quickly realized that it was so much easier to work with and less resource-intensive (go figure). The language was so efficient as well as easy to use. My friends &lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyvillanueva.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Joey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://liamcarney.com/&quot;&gt;Liam&lt;/a&gt; were also in my class, and we frequently banded together to build things. We helped each other solve some basic problems and fixed each others&#39; code before handing in assignments. It was a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first semester ended that year, we headed into the second semester, which sucked. I missed being able to write code the last period of the day, but I never took it for granted. So anyway, on to the reason of this post. Soon after CS I, I thought of an idea. Why not start a CS club for kids who are actually interested in learning more? It would be an after school club for anybody who wanted to drop in and build something. I&#39;ve already written an email to my guidance counselor concerning the topic. She then forwarded it to most of the head faculty in my school. So from here it looks pretty good for the CS club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&#39;ve been planning out how the club would actually function. I can almost see my vision before me of exactly how it&#39;d be. A small computer lab off to the side of the dark hallway after school hours. A bright-lit room filled with desktops, laptops, notebooks, and whiteboards. A room with a perfectly-sized group of kids hanging out and having fun. Then me, just chilling on my laptop hacking up some new software while sipping a coffee. I know it sounds silly (which it should, sort of) but it&#39;s my dream for this to occur. I know I can make this a reality, and as of now, it&#39;s all about waiting until September.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/csclub</id>
      <updated>2013-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/hello" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello world, this is the home of my new blog. I am somewhat sad to leave tumblr, but I am also very excited to begin using Jekyll, as well as hosting my blog here on GitHub. I was planning on leaving tumblr eventually for a new, free blogging platform anyway, because I feel as if tumblr doesn&#39;t give me that classic blog feel. I wanted a blog where I could link my posts to actual URLs, remove the &#39;Follow on tumblr&#39; button, remove the dashboard, and not have notes on my posts. I&#39;ve always wanted my own classic blog, one where it was plain and simple. It feels awesome having a small space on the Internet to call yours, it really does. FOr history-sake, attached below is a screenshot of my old blog I designed myself in nothing but HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I created it on Christmas Eve, and the last time it was active was around March when I transferred to tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FrHsTAE.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I will be able to attract more readers to my new blog, as I will be updating it more often. Have a great day everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/hello</id>
      <updated>2013-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Summer</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/summer" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello all, thought I’d update my few readers on what I’ve been up to. First off, I know I’m terrible at updating this blog, and I am aware that it is also a very sucky blog, but I still try and update it with as much interesting things as possible. I got out of school June 18, and finished off pretty well. All B+ grades, and one C in my computer aided design class. I know, I’m supposed to be good with computers, but design wasn’t really ever my thing. It was hard then easy, then hard then easy again. The final for the class was annoying, although I wish there were a better word to better describe it. We had such limited time, and the drawings were so confusing to recreate. The teacher could’ve said our recreations weren’t just like the picture. But what would he expect? All styles are supposed to be different, and of a noticeable difference. So anyway, July 1-9 I was away in Washington state, about 30 minutes outside of Portland, Oregon. I’ve been out to the northwest many times before, but I wasn’t ever so aware of the almost complete difference than the northeast where I’ve lived my whole life. The environment is different, the weather, the people, the stores, and just everything you’d expect to be. I’m glad to be home though. I’ve also gone back to work after my short vacation, and have just been installing Ubuntu Linux distributions on some of the machines that will be used for demos of our software. I do hope to be programming things soon, or have a more intriguing role in the office. This summer I’m supposed to be working with the code we currently have stored in a source version control system. That should be pretty cool, but I am terrified about how messy this code will be, especially dealing with my OCD as well. That’s all for now, and I’ll be sure to come back with better updates soon. Have a great week everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/summer</id>
      <updated>2013-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Quote</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/quote" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;“If you think you are beaten, you are,
If you think you dare not, you don’t.
If you like to win, but you think you can’t,
It is almost certain you won’t.
If you think you’ll lose, you’re lost,
For out in the world we find,
Success begins with a fellow’s will –
It’s all in the state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you are outclassed, you are,
You’ve got to think high to rise,
You’ve got to be sure of yourself before
You can ever win a prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life’s battles don’t always go
To the stronger or faster man
But soon or late the man who wins
Is the man who thinks he can.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Napoleon Hill, Think &amp;amp; Grow Rich&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/quote</id>
      <updated>2013-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Spring</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/spring" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello world, it’s finally spring. This time of the year usually makes me happier, due to the weather becoming warmer and being in the fresh air more often is always good. I rarely post on here because my life is usually not that interesting. But I’ve been keeping myself busy with a game I’ve been working on, that I’ve recently refactored and restarted development on it. I’m looking forward to working on it, and becoming more familiar with the Parse API, in which I’m using as my SQL alternative. Oh, and a software company called SellerCloud just opened up in an office next to my apartment complex, so I’ll definitely be stopping by there sometime this week. If it’s interesting over there, I might even see about an internship for awhile. This must be a sign, because neat things like this never seem to happen to me often. I’ll post an update soon on how everything’s going. Have a good night everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/spring</id>
      <updated>2013-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Random</title>
      <link href="http://imryan.net/blog/random" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is actually my first post here that’s written in awhile. It’s a bit off my blog theme, but I just wanted to log it. For awhile now, I don’t know what’s wrong with me. I’m never satisfied with anything I do. I can take 3 months creating a game, and when it’s done I’ll hate it. I can create a new Minecraft world, and a few days later be bored of it and hate it. I can start a game server, run it for a week, then hate it. Then a week later I’ll have an urge to do it again, and the cycle continues. I hate it. I can’t stand never being satisfied with anything. It started when I wanted to go to school in Jackson when I was in 8th grade. I always told my mom I hated my middle school in Lakewood, and I couldn’t wait to graduate. After I did, we moved to Jackson so I didn’t have to go to Lakewood High School. Once we moved to Jackson, I was excited to be with people I liked, and be back in public school. After a few months in, I started hating it. I couldn’t wait for freshman year to end. I haven’t seen most of my old friends from middle school in 2 years. We all don’t talk anymore really. My best friend doesn’t have any time left for me anymore after he’s been caught up with his new friends. I’m usually working or at home alone sometimes working on some project I’ll give up on by a week later. I don’t get what’s wrong with me, and it scares me. I get worked up easily when I’m overwhelmed, and I feel like I constantly work hard for nothing. In school I just feel like I don’t fit in. I feel extremely awkward and uncomfortable 75% of the time there, and I don’t feel like I belong there. I’m sorry if this was a bit personal, I just don’t get myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://imryan.net/blog/random</id>
      <updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ryan Cohen</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
